Menu

Menu

AdGuard Ad Blocker

AdGuard VPN

AdGuard DNS

Other products

Products

AdGuard Ad Blocker

Blocks ads, trackers, phishing, and web annoyances

AdGuard VPN

Makes you anonymous and your traffic inconspicuous

AdGuard DNS

A cloud-based DNS service that blocks ads and protects your privacy

Other products

Other tools for content blocking

EN

Dansk Deutsch English Español Français Hrvatski Italiano Magyar Nederlands Polski Português (BR) Português (PT) Română Slovenčina Slovenščina Srpski Suomi Tiếng Việt Türkçe Český Русский Українська 中文 (简体) 中文 (繁體) 日本語 한국어

[AdGuard DNS](https://adguard-dns.io/en/welcome.html) Privacy policy

AdGuard DNS Privacy Policy

June 5, 2024

Summary

We do not share or sell your personal information. We are strongly committed to protecting user privacy and being as transparent as possible.

1. The information we process includes no more than is crucial to provide the full functionality of AdGuard DNS, both public and private versions.
    
2. AdGuard DNS periodically connects to our servers to check updates and your subscription status.
    
3. When you sign up for our services or buy an AdGuard DNS subscription, you provide us with your email address. We’ll use it to notify you of changes to your AdGuard account. If you agree, we’ll also keep you informed about AdGuard DNS sales and news.
    
4. You are not required to share your personal data with us. You can delete your information by deleting your AdGuard account at [](https://my.adguard.com/)[https://my.adguard.com](https://my.adguard.com/) or by sending us a request at [privacy@adguard.com](mailto:privacy@adguard.com). Below, we list all the information we may process via AdGuard DNS and explain why we do it and how we use this information. We do not collect anything for tracking purposes and take all necessary measures to protect the information you share with us.

Who we are

ADGUARD SOFTWARE LIMITED (“We”, “Our” or “Us”) collects and processes your personal data in accordance with this Privacy Policy and in compliance with the applicable data protection laws. This Policy informs you of your rights and our obligations and explains how, why, and when we process your personal data. Our general principle is to collect only the information necessary to provide you with full functionality of our products and services. We strictly follow the principle of “minimization” when processing your data.

ADGUARD SOFTWARE LIMITED is a company registered in Limassol, Cyprus, registered office is at Anexartesias and Athinon 79, Nora Court Flat/Office 203-205, 3040 Limassol, Cyprus. ADGUARD SOFTWARE LIMITED acts as the data controller when processing your data.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or if you want to exercise any of your rights, please contact us at [privacy@adguard.com](mailto:privacy@adguard.com).

Please read this Privacy Policy thoroughly.

If you do not agree with our policies and practices described in this Privacy Policy, please do not use our software and services, do not visit our website, and do not provide your information to us.

What we do

AdGuard DNS operates as a DNS resolver that can block access to certain domains depending on the chosen configuration (server):

* AdGuard DNS Default blocks access to domains that we consider ad, tracking, or malware. [This list](https://adguardteam.github.io/AdGuardSDNSFilter/Filters/filter.txt) is constantly updated based on the community feedback.
    
* AdGuard DNS Family blocks access to the same domains as Default, and also to domains that may contain adult content. It also enforces safe search and other safe modes wherever possible, which can result in modified search results, missing comment sections, and other differences in the appearance of web pages compared to their original state.
    
* Non-filtering AdGuard DNS doesn’t block or redirect anything. It only returns the IP address of the requested domain.
    
* Private AdGuard DNS blocks DNS queries or modifies DNS responses in accordance with the user’s preferences. In addition to that, it displays the queries and statistics to the user via the AdGuard DNS dashboard. Registering an AdGuard account is required to use this type of DNS resolver.

If you disagree with our classification of a certain domain as advertising, tracking, malicious, or adult one, or if you believe a certain domain should be blocked by one of AdGuard DNS servers, contact us at [support@adguard-dns.io](mailto:support@adguard-dns.io).

What data we process and when

We process different data depending on the situation. You can learn details about what data we process in this section.

Some data that we receive and process may be treated as personal data (“Personal Data”) in accordance with the laws of certain territories and countries. When we use terms “personal data” or “personal information”, we mean any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person, excluding any anonymized and depersonalized data where your identity is absent or has been removed and cannot be recovered.

We do not collect anything about the user specifically, except where necessary to provide you with the functionality of AdGuard DNS.

* We store aggregated performance metrics of our DNS servers, namely the number of complete requests to a particular server, the number of blocked requests, and the speed of processing requests.
    
* We keep and store an anonymous database of domains requested in the last 24 hours. There is no information whatsoever that could link any of these domain names to the original user who sent the request. We need this information to identify and block new trackers and threats.
* We also log how many times this or that tracker has been blocked. We need this information to remove outdated rules from our filters.

All this data that we process is not shared with any third parties. It is used solely for internal purposes such as performance analytics. The only information we may share is derivative information, i.e., lists of domains that our servers recognize as advertising, tracking, or malicious.

When you are using our website

Account registration. We process your email address and a hash of the password you use for authorization. That ensures that you can retrieve your password if needed.

Sending messages. We can communicate with you using your email address when we have any announcements to make, to inform you about our software or service updates and new features, to advise or errors to report.

You can also provide us with your consent to process your email for sending marketing messages about our other software or services. You can withdraw your consent any time by unsubscribing from our newsletter via AdGuard Account or by clicking the “Unsubscribe” button or link in the email itself.

Cookies. We use our cookies for personalizing the content of the AdGuard DNS website, such as setting the default language. None of the information we may acquire through the use of cookies is considered Personal Data as it does not allow us to identify you. You can always disable or clear cookies in your browser, but please note that some of our services may not function properly without the aid of cookies. Please refer to the Privacy Policy of AdGuard Websites for details: [](https://adguard.com/website-privacy.html)[https://adguard.com/website-privacy.html](https://adguard.com/website-privacy.html).

Buying a subscription. If you purchase a subscription to Private AdGuard DNS, we’ll use the email address you provide to send you information about your purchase. We’ll also use your email address to create an account for you. This account will allow you to manage your purchased subscription.

We’ll also use your email address to create an account for you. This account will allow you to manage your purchased subscription.

We conduct all transactions via the Paddle payment provider [Paddle.com Inc.](https://www.paddle.com/) to enable payments if you purchase a subscription to use our software and services. The data processed depends on the payment provider and may include the following:

* Email address
    
* Country of residence
    
* Zip or postal code
    
* (If you use a bank card to make a purchase) Number, name, expiration date, and the security code associated with the bank card

For the exact data that the payment provider collects about you, please see the corresponding privacy policy: [Paddle’s Privacy Policy](https://www.paddle.com/legal/privacy).

When you are using public AdGuard DNS

We do not process any of your Personal Data when you connect to and use public AdGuard DNS.

However, we obtain and process general statistics on the use of public AdGuard DNS as we described above. This data is not linked to you in any way; it is accumulated when public AdGuard DNS is used by all users in general.

When you are using private AdGuard DNS

AdGuard DNS users may opt to use the “private AdGuard DNS” server. This functionality allows them to control their DNS queries, observe statistics and query logs.

In this case, AdGuard DNS will block DNS queries or modify them according to the user’s preferences.

We process the following data to enable you to use private AdGuard DNS:

* The email address you used to create your account.
* We store logs of DNS queries from connected devices in order to display it to you on the AdGuard DNS dashboard. Logs contain status and content of requests, names of companies who own the requested resources, names of connected devices, date of requests. Additionally, we will log anonymized IP addresses (limited to subnet) of connected devices from which incoming DNS requests are received, when this option is enabled by you. Users may opt to disable logging via the account settings. The log is only stored for a limited period of time which can also be configured via the account settings.

What legal bases we use to process your Personal Data

We use different legal bases to process Personal Data depending on the type of data, the purposes, and circumstances of processing.

Consent. We process your personal data if you have provided us with your consent to use your Personal Data for certain purposes. For example, to send you marketing messages or to help you troubleshoot problems with using our software. You can withdraw your consent any time without any detriment to your use of our software.

Performance of a contract. We process your Personal Data when it is necessary to fulfill our contractual obligations to you, including providing the functionality of our software and services or at your request prior to entering into a contract with you.

Legal obligations. We process your Personal Data where it is necessary for compliance with our legal obligations, such as to exercise or defend our legal rights, or for taxation purposes.

Legitimate interest. We process your Personal Data when we pursue our legitimate interests, except where such interests are overridden by the interests or fundamental rights and freedoms of data subjects.

Where we process your Personal Data

We store your Personal Data in our own data center located in Frankfurt. Your Personal Data may be processed by our employees, who can only access your data through their job duties on a need-to-know basis. If you have questions or want to know from which countries access may be possible, you can write to us at [privacy@adguard.com](mailto:privacy@adguard.com).

For data transfers to other countries, we always implement appropriate safeguards to ensure that your Personal Data always remains safe and that your rights are respected:

* The country or the third party is recognized as providing adequate protection.
    
* A valid transfer mechanism is applied such as the Standard Contractual Clauses and the supplementary measures are implemented, where necessary.
    
* The transfer has your explicit consent.
    
* The transfer is necessary for the performance of a contract with you or to take steps requested by you prior to entering into that contract.

If you would like a copy of the Standard Contractual Clauses used, please contact us at [privacy@adguard.com](mailto:privacy@adguard.com).

To determine if a non-EU country has an adequate level of data protection, please [the European Commission website](https://commission.europa.eu/law/law-topic/data-protection/international-dimension-data-protection/adequacy-decisions_en).

How we use your Personal Data

Retaining your data

We retain Personal Data for as long as necessary to continue providing you with our products and services, or until you revoke your consent to share this information.

Your rights

In some countries and regions, you may have certain rights in relation to your Personal Data under applicable data protection laws.

If you wish to exercise your rights with respect to your Personal Data, please contact us at [privacy@adguard.com](mailto:privacy@adguard.com). We will consider and act upon any request in accordance with applicable data protection laws. We may ask you to further confirm your identity and will respond to you within the time period specified by applicable data protection law. Please note that in certain cases stipulated by applicable data protection law, we may charge you a reasonable fee for processing your request or refuse your request.

You are entitled to exercise the following rights in relation to your Personal Data:

Right of access: the right to obtain all your Personal Data we store. In some cases, the right of access may be limited for technical reasons, including if the data has been anonymized and cannot be linked to any data subject.

Right to erasure or right to be forgotten: the right to completely delete your Personal Data. You can do this at will via AdGuard account, or by sending a request to [privacy@adguard.com](mailto:privacy@adguard.com).

Right to rectification: the right to correct any incomplete or inaccurate Personal Data about you. We will do so as quickly as possible, unless there is a valid reason not to, in which case you will be notified.

Right to restriction: the right to impose restrictions on processing of your Personal Data.

Right to object: the right to object to processing of your Personal Data.

Right to data portability: the right to receive provided Personal Data in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and to transmit that data to another controller. You can export all Personal Data that we hold about you to a local file from the AdGuard account on [](https://my.adguard.com/)[https://my.adguard.com](https://my.adguard.com/).

Right not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing, including profiling.

Right to withdraw a consent where the data processing is based on the consent.

Right to lodge a complaint with a data protection authority. You can find contact details of our data protection authorities [here](https://www.dataprotection.gov.cy/dataprotection/dataprotection.nsf/contact_en/contact_en?opendocument).

When we receive your Personal Data from a third party, we will use reasonable efforts to inform you about it.

Safeguarding measures

We make every possible effort to protect your Personal Data from unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure or destruction. We implement and maintain the following technical and security measures:

* System access controls: We take reasonable measures to prevent unauthorized use of Personal Data. These controls vary depending on the nature of the processing undertaken and may include, among other controls, authentication via passwords and/or two-factor authentication, documented authorization processes, documented change management processes, and/or logging of access on several levels.
    
* Data access controls: We take reasonable measures to ensure that Personal Data is accessed and managed only by properly authorized staff. Direct database query access is restricted and application access rights are established and enforced to ensure that individuals authorized to use a data processing system have access only to the Personal Data to which they have access privileges, and that Personal Data cannot be read, copied, modified, or removed during processing without authorization.
    
* Storing data in a data center: Personal information is stored in our own data center located in Frankfurt, Germany. This is secure — the data center does not demand that we collect any data about your traffic or your use of our products and services. If they request us to start doing so, we will stop using them and find an alternative.
    
* Transmission controls: We take reasonable measures to ensure that we are able to verify and determine the entities to which Personal Data is to be transmitted via data transmission facilities so that personal data cannot be read, copied, modified, or deleted without authorization during electronic transmission or in transit.
    
* Input controls: We take reasonable measures to ensure that it is possible to verify and establish whether and by whom personal data has been entered into, modified in, or removed from data processing systems.
    
* Data backup: Databases are backed up regularly, secured, and encrypted to ensure that Personal Data is protected from accidental destruction or loss when while in our possession.
    
* Logical separation: Personal Data is logically segregated on our systems to ensure that Personal Data collected for different purposes is processed separately.

Consequences of not providing your Personal Data

You are not obligated to provide your Personal Data to us. However, because this information is necessary for us to provide you with our services or respond to your enquiries, we will not be able to provide some or all of our services without it.

Age limitations

To the extent not prohibited by applicable law, we do not permit the use of our Services, Products and Website by anyone under the age of 18. If you learn that someone under the age of 18 has unlawfully provided us with Personal Data, please contact us and we will take steps to delete such information.

Changes to this Privacy Policy

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time and inform you of the important changes. Laws, regulations and industry standards evolve, which may require such changes, or we may make changes to our business. We will post the changes on this page and encourage you to review our Privacy Policy to stay informed.

Other documents:

© 2016–2024 AdGuard DNS

Site map

AdGuard DNS

Homepage Pricing Blog About us Connect to DNS AdGuard promo activities Media kits In the press

Other products

Support

Support center FAQ Knowledge base Version history Report an issue AdGuard status AdGuard diagnostics

Legal documents

Data Processing Agreement EULA Privacy policy Privacy policy of AdGuard websites Refund policy Terms and conditions Terms of sale
